

Marco Richetta

- Openhagen, Denmark
 □ marcorichetta@gmail.com
- marcorichetta.vercel.app | marco-richetta | narcorichetta

About Me

I like to share knowledge by giving talks, also as a mentor or simply helping others to solve problems. <u>E.g. the Django forum</u>.

Currently interested in enhancing **Developer Experience (DX)** through IaC. Also learning about Go, MLOps, Elixir.

My background is in backend but I like to look at the bigger picture and think beyond my specific role. Curiosity drives me but I'm always learning to balance it and prioritize impact.

Experience

Software Engineer, Mercado Libre - Córdoba, Argentina

Jul 2022 - Jun 2024

- Worked improving **Python DX**, maintaining tooling used by thousands of developers in the company. (General support, features, bugfixes, version deprecation).
- Building on our Python expertise, we led upgrades for over 1,000 outdated Java applications and libraries using <u>Large-Scale Code Changes</u>, managing the roadmap and collaborating with responsible teams to implement and monitor each update.

Software Developer, Flux IT - Córdoba, Argentina

Jan 2021 - Jun 2022

- Fullstack development (**React/Django**) to integrate 3rd party systems with internal company applications.
- Later, in a more **DevOps** role, I helped in the migration of the internal infrastructure to Kubernetes applying **GitOps**. This also led to better DX.

Education

BS Computer Systems Analyst, Instituto Superior 25 de Mayo – Feb 2015 - Dec 2020 Córdoba, Argentina

Volunteering

Hack Your Future: Joined as a Technical mentor to help people kickstart their programming carreers. - https://www.hackyourfuture.dk/

Technologies

Languages: Python, React, JavaScript/Typescript, Go

Technologies: Django, Pytest, Kubernetes, FluxCD, Docker, OpenTelemetry